In an adventurer party,
冒险者的队伍里 通常会有攻击手、补师等
I, Rud, am a tank.
我 路德的职业是肉盾
As the shield of the party,
身为队伍中的盾职
my duty is to block enemy attacks and protect my party members.
我负责挡下敌人的各种攻击 守护队伍同伴
It's a role where I play the unsung hero.
扮演的是无名英雄
This is the story of how a little guy like me…
这是讲述如此不起眼的我…
becomes the protagonist.
变成主角的故事
Oh, Big Brother,
哥哥 真是的
you never come back to see me. I've been so lonely.
你都不回来看看我 人家好寂寞喔
Manicia!
玛妮西娅！
Rud.
路德
I'm never going anywhere again.
哥哥之后哪里都不会去了！
Rud!
路德！
What's the big deal, Nin?
干吗啊？妮恩
I was having a great time in my fantasy…
我正沉浸在幸福的妄想中耶
Please stop making weird faces in the guild.
麻烦你不要在公会里 露出奇怪的表情好吗？
Sheesh.
真是的
Thinking about your little sister again?
你又在想你妹妹了吗？
You know me well.
你很清楚嘛
We're in the same party. I know that much about you.
毕竟我们是队伍同伴
You should consider picking up other interests.
偶尔也培养一些其他的嗜好嘛
Such as?
比方说呢？
Love… and stuff.
例如谈恋爱之类的
Nin, that's…
妮恩 那是…
Don't get the wrong--
等一下 路德
But there's no one cuter than Manicia.
-你误会… -没有人比玛妮西娅还可爱
So irritating.
让人不爽
Hey, Rud, I'm serious.
路德 我可是很认真的
Seriously speaking, though,
说正经的
I've been trying to keep my mind off of other things.
其实我一直刻意 让自己不去思考其他的事情
The only way to save Manicia from her incurable disease is
毕竟想拯救身患不治之症的玛妮西娅
to obtain the labyrinth treasure capable of granting all wishes.
就只能靠那个能实现 任何愿望的迷宫秘宝
Rud…
路德
But, considering my sorry state from yesterday, forget about the treasure,
但是啊
I let everyone down.
对大家也很抱歉
That's not true.
没有这回事
You did your duty as a tank.
你确实尽到了自己身为肉盾的职责
You weren't hit by the enemy,
当时明明没有被敌人打中
but your shield force's effect decreased.
但护盾却莫名减少 这情况太诡异了
It wasn't just yesterday either.
不只是昨天
During the recent labyrinth raids,
最近在攻略迷宫时
my shield force has been weakening before I know it.
我的护盾总是会在不知不觉间消耗掉
I've been using up a lot of recovery potions too.
而且我的回复药水也用得很凶
That must've put quite a burden on you, the healer.
对你这个补师造成了很大的负担
I'm truly sorry.
真的很抱歉
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊？
You're the reason we've been able
大家之所以能一路战斗到现在
to come this far.
都是因为有你在啊
I know you've been protecting me.
我很清楚 你一直在保护我
Besides, your shield has 9,999 resistance.
而且你的护盾有9999
That's the highest we've ever seen.
那可是历代最高的数值喔
Nin…
妮恩
You're an excellent tank.
你真的是一个很优秀的护盾
So, even if we get new party members, stand tall and proud.
所以就算来了新同伴 也要抬头挺胸地面对他们喔
It's the hero!
是勇者！
I heard he's already conquered several labyrinths at such a young age.
听说他年纪轻轻就攻略了好几座迷宫
That's the great hero, Kygras, for you.
不愧是勇者吉古拉斯大人
Yo, Rud.
嗨 路德
Sorry, am I late?
抱歉 我来晚了吗？
No, just on time.
不 时间刚好
Good morning, Lilia, Lily.
早安 莉莉亚、莉莉
Now that the party is all here, let me introduce everyone.
既然队伍的成员都到齐了
These are our new party members.
是新同伴喔
Hold on, Kygras.
等等 吉古拉斯
What's going on here?
这到底是怎么一回事？
The rule is that a party can only have up to six members.
攻略迷宫的规则 是一个队伍最多只能六个人喔
Doesn't this make it seven?
这样不就变成七个人了吗？
Don't worry.
别担心
The party will still have six.
队伍会剩下六个人的
Rud, you are dismissed as of today.
路德 你在今天被开除了
Why?
为什么？
Obviously,
-当然是因为你没能尽到… -暴风炸裂！
Life Burst!
生命爆发！
We did it!
太好了
You lost your shield force entirely yesterday.
你昨天不是一下子 就把护盾都耗尽了吗？
That's the problem.
那就是主要原因啊
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Stop messing around!
别开玩笑了！
How can we continue with such a useless tank?
肉盾这么弱 是要怎么继续前进啊？
No…
不…
Wait.
给我等一下
Rud blocked the attacks,
路德明明在好好挡下敌人的攻击
but the shield still wore off.
然而护盾还是自行损耗了
There must be some other reason behind it.
这肯定是其他原因导致的啊
We know it's his skills.
想也知道是他的技能在搞鬼啊
-His two skills with unknown effects. -Rud, come on!
-毕竟他有两个效果不明的技能 -糟糕 路德 快点！
but we still don't know for sure if his skills were the cause of it.
但是现在还不知道 是不是他的技能害的
-Yet… -What are you going on about?
-结果你却… -你说那是什么鬼话？
If we weren't careful, we could've been wiped out.
要是一个不小心 我们可能会全灭
Isn't that enough reason to dismiss him?
这个理由就足够让我开除他了吧？
Besides, our new member here is
而且这位新加入的同伴
the evasion-type tank that's all the rage these days.
可是最近很流行的回避型肉盾喔
She can even attack while she dodges.
不仅能闪过攻击 还能同时攻击
She's a far cry from you, who can only defend.
跟只能防守的你 简直是天壤之别
For all these reasons,
综合上述原因
you're dismissed.
你被开除了
It can't be helped…
是啊
I understand.
我知道了
Rud…
路德
Hey, I'm not finished yet.
喂 我还没说完呢
Because of you, we didn't get any rewards yesterday.
昨天因为你的关系 都没拿到报酬
The highest endurance stats we've ever seen? Bah.
什么历代最高的护盾数值啊？
You're just a lousy tank who can't even use your shield properly.
根本是个只会随便消耗 护盾的废物肉盾嘛！
We know you're capable.
我们知道你很有实力
Good luck.
总之加油吧
You invited me to join the party,
亏你还邀我组队
but it seems my abilities weren't up to par.
可惜我的能力好像不太够呢
That's not true at all!
才没有那种事！
Rud, are you really leaving?
我问你 路德 你真的要与我分开吗？
I told you about the town my little sister and I live in, right?
我之前和你提过
Avancia, right?
是阿凡锡亚吧？
What about it?
怎么了吗？
You can come find me there.
只要你过来找我就可以了
I won't always be there,
虽然不是无时无刻都在那里
but I'm planning on moving back to live with my sister there permanently.
但我今后打算回故乡和妹妹生活
That's why
所以…
we'll meet again someday.
我们之后还有机会见面的
But it's not like I'll be that lonely without you.
不过其实我也没有感到寂寞啦
I know.
我知道啦
I'm looking forward to the next time we meet again.
我会期待未来再次与你相会的
So, what should I do now?
那么接下来要怎么办呢？
Though I want to return to Avancia…
-虽然想回阿凡锡亚… -喂 快点搬啊
You're just a lousy tank who can't even use your shield properly.
根本是个只会随便消耗 护盾的废物肉盾嘛！
That a skill of mine was depleting my shield force?
是我的技能 在不知不觉间消耗护盾吗？
Doesn't that make it a defective skill?
那不就真的是个没用技能了吗？
It makes me uneasy, but I don't know anyone who can appraise it for me.
尽管感到不安 但现在又没办法拜托别人帮忙鉴定
Anyway, are we sure
话说回来 光靠我们几个
we can handle this escort mission?
真的能胜任护卫的委托吗？
We've all risen to D-rank. We can handle it just fine.
我们都已经升上D位阶了 肯定没问题啦
But…
可是…
AVANCIA, KURATH CURRENT LOCATION
（阿凡锡亚 库拉斯 现在位置）
Excuse me.
可以打扰一下吗？
He's huge!
好高大！
About that mission… May I join you?
你们说的那个委托 可以让我一起参加吗？
I won't need any payment.
不用给我报酬没关系
Truth be told, I'm still at F-rank
老实说 我现在还是F位阶
because of all the time I spent in the labyrinths…
因为之前老是待在迷宫
-Stare…
-盯
I've seen him somewhere…
我好像在哪里看过这个人
I remember now!
我想起来了 他是勇者队伍里的人！
Actually, I…
不 但是我…
Everyone.
各位
You must be the adventurers who accepted the request.
你们就是承接委托的冒险者吧？
Yes.
是的
We have a new party member.
我们新增了一位同伴
What's your name?
您叫什么名字呢？
I… I'm Rud.
我叫路德
Mister Rud, yes?
路德先生 是吧？
I don't mind,
没问题喔
but I can't offer a higher reward.
只是报酬没办法再提高了
Off we go, then.
那我们要出发了
Please.
麻烦您了
I missed the timing to tell them my rank.
错过和他们说明位阶的时机了
I feel bad keeping it from them, but there's no other choice.
这样很像在骗他们 实在不好意思
I'll ensure their safety
到库拉斯镇为止 要好好担任护卫才行
It's foggy.
起雾了呢
Let's stop here for the night.
今天就在这边歇息吧
No, we're almost at Kurath, aren't we?
不 我们快到库拉斯了吧
I have a bad feeling about this.
我有种不好的预感
Let's cross this forest in one go.
还是一口气穿过这片森林吧
I understand.
我知道了
As long as we keep an eye out for ambushes,
只要注意别被突袭
we should reach Kurath safely.
应该就能平安抵达库拉斯了吧
Please stop the carriage.
请停车
Is something the matter?
发生什么事了吗？
Is it a monster?
是魔物吗？
It could be bandits or something else.
也有可能是盗贼之类的
You guys stay here.
你们先留在这里
You over there!
喂 那边的家伙！
I don't sense anyone around.
周遭没有其他人的气息
It's not a trap.
看来应该不是陷阱
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
There's no need to be scared.
你不用感到害怕
I won't hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
Can you stand?
站得起来吗？
She… She's naked!
她居然没穿衣服
A magic stone?
魔石？
Is she…
难道这孩子是…
Mister Rud, monster!
路德先生 魔物出现了！
It's the Forest Snake!
是森林大蛇！
It's massive!
这也太大只了吧！
Find cover.
你快去躲起来
This snake's venom is highly toxic.
各位 那家伙的毒很危险
You must be careful.
还请小心避开！
This isn't a monster we can defeat!
这不是我们打得赢的魔物啊！
Are we going to die here?
难道我们要死在这里了吗？
Over here, Forest Snake!
给我看过来 森林大蛇！
Taunt!
挑衅！
Mister Rud!
路德先生！
My skill makes me immune to status effects.
我有不会陷入任何异常状态的技能
I'll distract it
我会吸引它的注意 你们负责进攻
Even if you say that…
就算您叫我们进攻…
What should we do?
该怎么办才好？
At this rate…
这样下去的话…
Manicia!
玛妮西娅！
Big Brother…
哥哥
I can't die here.
我绝不能死在这种地方
You guys.
你们几个！
I don't have a sword with me.
我手边现在没有剑
We can't defeat this thing unless you attack.
如果你们不动手 就无法斩杀这家伙
Grab your weapons and move.
好好握住武器 动起来吧
We'll take it down together!
让我们一起击败它！
As the strongest tank,
身为最强肉盾的我
I will block…
绝对会挡下…
all of its attacks!
那家伙的所有攻击！
So, please,
所以你们也要相信自己的力量
You will
你们绝对…
conquer it!
会赢的！
Now!
就是现在！
That's…
那是…
Watch out!
各位 它要使出必杀技了！
Dodge!
赶紧躲开啊！
I can't do that.
我不能躲开
Precisely because it's an ultimate attack…
正因为是必杀技
I must block it.
挡下来才有意义啊！
Now!
就是现在！
I can't believe we defeated the Forest Snake!
没想到我们居然能打败森林大蛇
We couldn't have done it on our own.
光靠我们几个肯定无法打败它
It's all thanks to Mister Rud.
都是多亏有路德先生在场
It's because we all did our part.
这是因为我们尽到了各自的职责啦
Now, I'll leave you to dismantle the monster.
那么就拜托你们肢解魔物了
I'm going to check on the girl.
我去确认一下那个女孩子的状况
Got it.
我知道了
-Are you hurt? -No.
-你没受伤吧？ -没有
That's good to hear.
太好了
You were running away from that monster, right?
你刚才是遇到魔物才会逃到这里吧？
What are your plans after this?
之后有什么打算呢？
Do you have anywhere you can go?
有可以去的地方吗？
I don't know where I should go…
我没有能去的地方
In that case,
那么…
will you come with me?
你要跟我一起走吗？
I'm headed to a town named Avancia.
我正要前往一个叫阿凡锡亚的城镇
Can I?
我可以跟您一起走吗？
If you don't mind.
如果你不排斥的话
Of course not.
我怎么会排斥呢？
All right. But…
很好 不过…
you can't exactly go around dressed like that.
你那副打扮实在是不太妙呢
If you don't mind, you can have these clothes.
不介意的话请收下这件衣服吧
Are you sure?
真的可以吗？
Of course.
当然没问题
We'd be dead if it weren't for you.
毕竟没有路德先生的话我们早就死了
Consider it a token of my appreciation.
这是我的一点回礼
Go get changed over there.
你去那边换衣服吧
Okay.
好的
Could that child be a runaway slave?
那孩子会不会是逃跑的奴隶呢？
Normally, an enslaved Homunculus
身为人类奴隶的人造人
would never act on its own.
在一般状况下应该不会单独行动
There might be something going on.
或许是有什么隐情吧
Slave traders usually wouldn't go through such a dangerous forest.
奴隶商人通常不会 特地通过这种危险的森林
Plus, she doesn't have a collar on her.
而且她也没戴项圈
Thank you.
谢谢您载我们一程
Is it all right for us to drop you off here?
真的送到这里就好了吗？
Yes.
是的
Well, then, we will take our leave now.
那么我们就先告辞了
Please wait.
请稍等一下
Mister Rud, do you have a party at the moment?
路德先生现在在和别人组队吗？
No, I don't.
不 没有
We'd like to take adventures with a strong tank like you.
我们想和路德先生 这种强大的肉盾一起冒险
I appreciate the invitation,
你们邀请我 我很开心
but I'm on a search for the labyrinth treasure.
不过我必须去取得秘宝才行
As in
是指可以实现 任何愿望的那个秘宝吗？
And the power to create Homunculi.
除此之外 还能拥有创造人造人的技术
Yes, that's right.
是啊
Homunculus, huh?
人造人啊？
I'm not good at dealing with Homunculi.
我不太擅长和人造人接触
They're always working emotionlessly.
因为他们总是面无表情地做事
I find that quite unsettling.
总觉得挺可怕的
The only difference in appearance is
但他们与我们的外貌差异
the magic stone embedded in their chests.
也就只差在胸口是否嵌有魔石吧
Still…
可是…
And that's why
事情就是这样
I can't join your party. I'm sorry.
所以我无法跟你们走 不好意思
I see.
这样啊
Mister Rud,
如果是路德先生
I'm sure your labyrinth raids will be successful.
肯定能顺利攻略迷宫的！
That reminds me. I guess I haven't introduced myself yet.
对了 我好像还没自我介绍吧
My name is Rud.
我叫做路德
Mister Rud…
路德先生
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
I don't have a name.
我没有名字
I see.
这样啊
Well, it'll be hard to call you without one.
没有名字的话 不太好称呼你呢
Those are Lunafia petals.
那是露娜菲亚的花瓣
Luna.
露娜
Luna?
露娜吗？
If you don't like it, you can change it later.
如果你不喜欢可以之后再更换
No, it's fine.
不
Thank you for giving me a name.
谢谢您帮我取名字
Thank you for the food.
多谢款待
Let's get an early night.
我们早点休息吧
Okay.
好的
So Luna really is an illegally created Homunculus.
所以露娜果然是 违法制造出来的人造人啊
She has free will and emotions unlike regular Homunculi,
她拥有普通人造人所没有的 自我意识和情感
and she can even fight.
甚至还能战斗
Normally, illegally created Homunculi are supposed to be destroyed.
照理来说
But her terrified expression
不过她当时惊恐的眼神
reminded me of Manicia.
让我想起了玛妮西娅
I couldn't just leave her be.
总觉得无法放任不管
I'm sorry about the pot.
抱歉 打翻了锅子
It's all right. We've finished eating anyway.
没事 反正我们都吃饱了
That said,
不过既然你这么强 应该也能打倒森林大蛇吧
I… I'm more proficient in using magic.
我比较擅长用魔法
I don't have any melee skills.
一个近战系的技能都没有
Magic.
魔法啊
I wonder if she's able to imitate and simulate magic skills.
不知道她能不能将技能模拟重现出来
Do you have any magic skills?
你有魔法系的技能吗？
I have a skill that enhances magic.
我有可以强化魔法的技能
Anything else?
还有其他的吗？
I have a support skill.
有一个辅助系的技能
I see. Appraisal, huh?
原来如此 是鉴定啊
Appraisal?
-鉴定？ -是的
Only one person in a neighboring country had this skill.
听说至今只有 邻国的某个人拥有这个技能
That person passed away a few years ago.
可惜那个人在几年前过世了
In other words, you're the only one in the world who has Appraisal now.
也就是说现在这个世上 拥有鉴定技能的人就只剩你了
I had no idea it was such a prized skill.
原来是这么珍贵的技能啊
Can you help appraise my skills?
你能帮忙鉴定一下我的技能吗？
Of… Of course.
没问题喔
Really?
真的可以吗？
It's my job, after all.
毕竟那就是我的工作呀
Now, then,
那么因为发动技能需要接触对方
so please excuse me.
恕我失礼
You have four skills, Mister Rud.
路德先生有四个技能
First, Taunt.
首先是“挑衅”
It's a skill that attracts as much attention as possible from the enemy.
是一种可以尽可能 吸引敌人注意力的技能
Next, Strong Body.
接着是“强健肉体”
It makes the bearer immune to status effects,
不仅能让持有者不会陷入异常状态
and enhances self-recovery
还能提升自主回复的能力
and maximizes the body's vitality and strength.
甚至能让身体的强壮程度达到极限
I already knew about these two skills. The real deal is what comes after.
这两个技能我本来就知道了
Then, you have Life Conversion.
再来是“生命转换”
Life Conversion is a skill
所谓的“生命转换”
that allows you to turn the shield force consumed in battle into power.
是能将战斗时 损耗的护盾转换成力量的技能
So
也就是说 这是攻击系技能吗？
It appears so.
似乎是这样没错
It seems some skills cannot be invoked until you understand it.
看来有些技能 得先理解其概念才有办法使用呢
Finally…
最后是…
Sacrificial Shield.
“牺牲之盾”
Sacrificial Shield?
牺牲之盾？
The Sacrificial Shield allows the wielder to bear the damage
所谓的“牺牲之盾”
inflicted on their comrades.
能将其伤害转移到自己身上的技能
And it enhances the resilience of both the comrades
此外 在掩护同伴的期间
and oneself while protecting the party.
似乎还能强化同伴和自身的强韧度
It transfers damage to myself?
将别人的伤害转移到自己身上？
Yes, that's right.
没错 正是如此
So, the weakening of my shield force was
所以我的护盾之前会莫名其妙损耗
because I was protecting my party members all along?
其实是牺牲之盾 让我代替队伍成员承受了伤害
Is something wrong?
怎么了吗？
Nothing.
没事
It's just that my concern over my unknown skills
我长久以来一直在为未知技能所烦恼
that had been troubling me for so long was resolved so easily.
没想到这么轻易就烟消云散了
Thank you, Luna.
谢谢你 露娜
It's my honor to be of help.
能帮上忙是我的荣幸
I was kicked out of the party because of my skills
虽然我因为拥有效果不明的技能
that I wasn't aware of.
而被赶出队伍
But now I know
但我现在知道自己的技能
that my skills are the most powerful for protecting my comrades.
其实是能守护同伴的最强技能
I can return home with my head held high,
这下能抬头挺胸回故乡了
back to Avancia, where my little sister awaits.
回到有妹妹等着我的阿凡锡亚